

# Thomas Carter

### Seasoned IT Professional

Successful IT Professional with years experience in Fortune 100 Companies.

Expertise in the areas of communicating technical functionality to non-technical people, process improvement, training, and customer enhancements. Always flexible and change adaptable. You can have several paragraphs or add links.

## **Work Experience**

### Fulfillment Ambassador

Amazon

July 2016 - August 2017

Provides quality inventory control by identifying defects. Train day one employees as well as cross-train existing staff.

### **Operations Analyst**

Blue Cross Blue Shield MN

2004 - 2007

Automated Operations of the host systems using primarily OPS/MVS

#### Key contributions:

- Reduced inefficiencies in the automation code by more than 60% on all lpars by consolidating programs/rules and eliminating unnecessary code.
- Saved the company thousands of dollars per month by leading and completing the conversion of all mainframe Netview automation processes to OPS/MVS by creating a new REXX program and RDF table (for SQL queries).
- Improved efficiencies in problem management by converting console WTO/WTOR (Write to Operator Replies) to automated problem tickets on Tivoli.

### Computer Scheduling Analyst

**Alternative Resources Corporation** 

2004 - 2004

SME for IBM Global Services effort to convert from Zeke/Zebb computer scheduling software to Jobtrac/CA11 on the Ameriprise systems.

### Key contributions:

• Significantly advanced the conversion of several applications while managing many of the issues on the project plan and providing expert advice to the team.

Automated Operations of the host systems using several software products.

### Key contributions:

- Continuously improved processing environment for the customer by maintaining over 1 million lines of automation code and providing oncall support.
- Ensured a seamless approach to our mainframe scheduling conversion project through role as SME(subject matter experts).
- Negotiated with customers to improve many of their enhancement requests without compromising their effectiveness.
- Enhanced automation processes by successfully converting from AF-Operator software to more reliable and robust OPS/MVS.

# Systems Management Integration Professional

**International Business Machines** 

1999 - 2003

8/20/2018 Thomas Carter | Resume

### **Staff Engineer**

American Express Financial Advisors

1993 - 1999

Technical leadership of the batch scheduling process.

Key contributions:

- Provided technical leadership for the scheduling team by teaching advanced scheduling methods, resulting in more consistent and flexible service to clients.
- Eliminated delays to the customer's batch processes by designing a system to initiate batch flow, eliminating unnecessary handoffs and creating greater time efficiencies.
- Designed and taught a two hour class on scheduling and rerun software for broad technical audience resulting in increased product knowledge for application programmers, operations personnel, and technical support.
- Reduced expenses by working in a dual role as analyst for the continuous disaster recovery project to ensure all critical files to the business were backed up daily at a synchronized time.

### **Education**

### Web Development Bootcamp, April 2018 - June 2018

Udemy course online: Instructed by Colt Steele

### Javascript Introduction, January, 2018 - March, 2018

EDX online course: Instructed by Michel Buffa (W3C)

### Lynda (online), 2017

HTML and CSS classes

### Metro State University, graduated 1991

Self-designed B.A., Business and Communications

### OpsXchange CA and Protech, Pittsburgh, PA

OPS/MVS related classes

# Let's Keep in Touch!

thomas.s.carter@live.com

LinkedIn

Copyright 2017 by Thomas Carter